They wanted New York's lights.
Brunson wanted the smoke.
Heavy is the crown, but Jalen Brunson wore
it like a fitted.
This is not LA, where losing can get
dressed up as lifestyle.
This is not Miami, where the crowd shows up late
and leaves before the fourth gets dangerous.
This is not Boston, where one day they call
you Jesus and the next day you are Judas.
This is New York. This is the Knicks.
The Garden can smell fear before the ball
even hits the rim.
For years, the biggest names had every
excuse in the book.
The timing was wrong.
The roster was wrong.
The front office was wrong.
The pressure was too much. Cool.
Knicks fans heard all of it.
As a Knicks fan, it seemed like they were
afraid.
Afraid of the Garden turning on them.
Afraid of the back page.
Afraid of coming to New York, failing, and
having New Yorkers remind them forever.
They wanted New York's lights.
They did not want New York's smoke.
And Brooklyn?
Brooklyn is not the Knicks.
The Nets are not even the little brother.
They are the distant relative.
Same city. Different weight.
You can hoop in New York without carrying
New York.
The Knicks are different.
The Garden is different.
That orange and blue is different.
And Brunson knew that. He chose it anyway.
Read or listen to the full essay.
Heavy Is The Crown. Brunson Wanted The
Smoke.
journal.kaliartistry.com